middleburyinteractive.com 2014-11-29

# Privacy Policy | Middlebury Interactive Languages

Middlebury Interactive Languages, LLC has established this privacy policy to let you know how we collect, use, share and protect information that we may gather from middleburyinteractive.com, powerspeak.com, and mmla.middlebury.edu (collectively, "Sites"). This policy does not apply to information that we may collect from you outside of our Sites, such as over the phone, by fax, or through conventional mail. In addition, please note that all of your children's educational records are protected by MIL as required by the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act and similar state laws.

### Non-Personal and Aggregated Information Collected Automatically

Each time you visit our website, we log non-personal information. Such information includes your IP address, domain name, the name of the Web page from which you entered our website, which pages you visit on our website, and how much time you spend on each page. We use this information to monitor and improve our website and for internal analysis. In particular, we use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the website, and gather information for aggregate use. However, IP addresses are not linked to personal information.

### Use of Cookies 

Our website uses "cookies" to help personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you. We use cookies to keep track of how you are using the Sites to tailor Web content to your interests. MIL cookies do not contain personal information about the parent(s) or children enrolled in MIL’s Services.

We will not share or sell non-aggregated information contained within cookies to any third party.

You also have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If, however, you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of our Sites or have some of our services on the Sites function properly.

### Personal Information You Provide

You can use portions of our Sites without divulging any personal information, including your e-mail address. Our Sites do not collect personal information about individuals except when such individuals specifically provide such information on a voluntary basis (for example, requesting a catalog; requesting additional information by contacting us; posting a message to a message board; or requesting help). When you register your children for a MIL Service or register or participate in a MIL Service through an affiliate or local school, we may collect information regarding you and your children. This personal information may be collected on our Sites, or via telephone or conventional mail. The types of information that you may be asked to provide, depending on what services you would like to receive, include: first and last name; billing address; the names and ages of your children; the services you request; registration and enrollment information about your children; and an e-mail address where we can contact you.

Once you have registered your children for a MIL Service (whether you registered on our Sites, or through offline communications), there is an online service for all such programs (collectively, the "OLS"). There will be a personal information page on the OLS that contains some or all of your personal information. You may also be assigned a Member ID and password and may create, at your discretion, a Member ID for your children any time you are logged on to the OLS. The Member ID will be used to recognize you and your children on the OLS portion of the MIL Site. The Member ID will allow MIL to recognize: your first and last name; registration ID; type of account, such as teacher, administrator, parent or student (if you created a separate Member ID and password for your children); school affiliation or the MIL Service in which your children are enrolled; integration number; and the e-mail address you provided. The Member ID and the OLS will also allow you to track your children's attendance, school work, and testing, and to submit relevant portions of same to MIL, its affiliates, and/or your local school to track your children's progress and abide by State and/or Federal standards and regulations.

MIL, its affiliates, and/or your local school may use personal information provided by you on your account information page on OLS to contact you about your children's progress, testing, attendance, customer service, and quality control procedures. To the extent that third party vendors assist MIL and/or its affiliates in the provision of online products or services, those vendors are provided the minimum amount of data required to perform the tasks for which they have been engaged. They have no independent rights to such data and have agreed to adhere to the MIL Privacy Policy.

MIL may use the personal information on your account information page on OLS to provide you with information about new products and services available through MIL. You can request to opt out of receiving such information by making a request in writing to privacy@middleburyinteractive.com. 

MIL may share your information with companies that are not affiliated with MIL but who are interested in sending you information about their products and services. You can request that your personal information not be shared with independent third parties by making a request in writing to privacy@middleburyinteractive.com.

You can review and edit the personal information that you have provided to MIL by making a request in writing to privacy@middleburyinteractive.com

### Personal Information Provided by Parents About Children

We understand that our student users who are under 13 years of age need special safeguards and privacy protection, and it is our intent to fully comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). MIL does not collect personal information from children online at any point. MIL only receives personal information about your children directly from you when you enroll your children into a MIL Service. You can review certain personal information that MIL has regarding your children by making such a request in writing to privacy@middleburyinteractive.com Please be aware that some personal information relating to your children's educational records may not be able to be disclosed by MIL due to state and/or Federal law.

You can request that your children's personal information not be used by MIL, its affiliates and vendors acting on behalf of MIL, by making a request in writing to privacy@middleburyinteractive.com Please be aware that if you make such a request, your children can no longer continue to be enrolled in an MIL Service. Therefore, a request by you for MIL, affiliates, and vendors acting on behalf of MIL to no longer use your children's personal information will terminate your children's participation in the MIL Service in which they are enrolled.

For information on COPPA and the use of children's personal information, please contact:

Middlebury Interactive Languages, LLC  
23 Pond Lane  
Middlebury, VT 05753  
privacy@middleburyinteractive.com 

### Message Boards and Chats

We may offer MIL message boards and chat rooms to you, the parent(s), on our Sites. Please be aware that anyone may read your postings on a message board or in a chat room. Furthermore, any information which you submit to be posted to a message board or in a chat room, including your information from your account information page and Member ID, will be disclosed and available to all users of that message board or chat room, and is therefore no longer private. We cannot guarantee the security of such information that you disclose or communicate online in public areas such as message boards and chat rooms, and you do so at your own risk. We reserve the right to monitor the content of the message boards only and to republish your postings from message boards or chat rooms elsewhere on the Web or otherwise in any format.

### Links

The Sites may contain links to other websites, chat rooms, or other resources that we provide for your convenience ("Linked Sites"). These sites are not under the control of MIL, and MIL is not responsible for the content available on any Linked Site. Such links do not imply MIL's endorsement of material on any Linked Site, and MIL expressly disclaims all liability with regard to your access to such Linked Sites. Access to any other websites linked to the Sites is at your own risk.

### Our Commitment to Data Security

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place commercially reasonable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect. We also use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol on your account information and registration pages to protect sensitive personal information.

### Changes in Corporate Structure

If all or part of Middlebury Interactive Languages, LLC or any of its affiliates are sold, merged or otherwise transferred to another entity, the personal information you have provided at these Sites may be transferred as part of that transaction or process. However, MIL will take steps to assure that the personal information is used in a manner consistent with the MIL privacy policy under which it was collected. The Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act protects your children's educational records, in the event of such a transaction or transfer.

### Changes to the Privacy Policy

We will occasionally amend this Privacy Policy to reflect company and customer feedback. We reserve the right to change, modify, add, or remove portions of this policy at any time. If MIL materially changes its use of your personal information we will note it in this Privacy Policy. The effective date of this Privacy Policy is documented at the end of the Privacy Policy. If you have any questions about MIL's privacy policy, please contact us in writing at privacy@middleburyinteractive.com.

Privacy Policy last updated November 15, 2013.
